Day, Edmund Ezra Collection of Bell Aircraft Corporation and UAW, Local 501 Arbitration Files 5094
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Edmund Ezra Day Collection of Bell Aircraft Corporation and UAW, Local 501 Arbitration Files
1949
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Day, Edmund Ezra
Bell Arcraft Corporation
International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW)
International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America
5094
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Bell Aircraft Corporation and the United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers International Union Local 501: arbitration files, 1949.
3117816
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 14, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 28, 2016
Biographical / Historical
This dispute arose over the application of security regulations and economic demands during the renegotiation of the contract. A strike ensued and the company secured an injunction to restrain the mass picketing. Violence resulted in the arrest of some of the strikers. The Commissioner of Labor, Mr. Edward Corsi, appointed a fact-finding board consisting of Edmund Ezra Day, Chairman; DR. Samuel P Copen, Mr. Charles Garside, Mrs. Elinore Herrick and Paul S. Andrews.
Scope and Contents
Bell Aircraft Corporation and the United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers International Union Local 501: arbitration files, 1949. Contained in this collection are 9 volumes, totaling 1659 pages, includig correspondence, newspapers clippings, exhibits, and materials from the hearing on the injunction.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Airlines -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- Sources; Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951.; Bell Aircraft Corporation; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (CIO)
3117816
- Union's Brief on Proposed Changes in the 1949 Collective Bargaining Agreement - Bell Aircraft Corporation and Local 501 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Award of Board Inquiry for Arbitration Between Bell Aircraft and Local 501 (1/10/1950) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Union Position on Proposed Contract (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Clippings (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Award of Board Inquiry Regarding Arbitration Between Bell Aircraft Corporation and Local 501 (1/10/1950) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Award of Board Inquiry - Bell Aircraft Corporation and Local 501 (1/10/1950) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Union Position of Proposed Contract (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Board (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and Communications (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Conflicting Data (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Awards and Clippings (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bell Wage Rates and Retirement Plan (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bell Aircraft Corporation (Wheatfield Plant) - Wage Rate Charts 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bell Dispute Agreements Reached (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Andrew's Draft of the Award (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Interim Award (Box 1, Folder 17)
- UAW-Bell Agreement (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Agreements and Documents and Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Board of Inquiry Report (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Contracts Signed With and Without Wage Increases (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Agreement Between Bell Aircraft Corporation and Local 501 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Union's Brief on Proposed Changes in the 1949 Collective Bargaining Agreement Between Bell Aircraft Corporation and Local 501 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- NYS Board of Inquiry - Bell Aircraft Corporation and Local 501 Memorandum Brief (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Company Position on Proposed Contract (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Data on the NYS Strike and Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Board of Inquiry Hearings (October 2,1949 - December 7, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Bell-UAW (December 6, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Board of Arbitration: Bell-UAW (November 23,1949) (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Board of Arbitration: Bell-UAW (November 21-22, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Board of Arbitration: Bell-UAW (November 1, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Board of Inquiry: Bell-UAW (October 15, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Board of Arbitration: Bell-UAW (October 26-28) (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Board of Inquiry: Bell-UAW (October 14,1949) (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Board of Inquiry: Bell-UAW (October 12,1949) (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Board of Inquiry: Bell-UAW (October 13,1949) (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Supreme Court, Niagara County (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Board of Inquiry: Bell-UAW (December 7, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 38)